the training of the model and making it really large.
So I think scale will be the primary determining factor.
It's like the first principle component of things, for sure.
But there are many of the other things that you need to get right.
So it's almost like the scale sets some kind of a speed limit almost.
But you do need some of the other things,
but it's like if you don't have the scale,
then you fundamentally just can't train some of these massive models
if you are going to be training models.
If you're just going to be doing fine tuning and so on,
then I think maybe less scale is necessary.
But we haven't really seen that just yet to fully play out.
And can you share more about some of the ingredients
that you think also matter,
maybe lower in priority behind scale?
Yeah, so the first thing I think is like
you can't just train these models.
If you're just given the money and the scale,
it's actually still really hard to build these models.
And part of it is that the infrastructure is still so new
and it's still being developed and not quite there.
But training these models at scale is extremely difficult
and is a very complicated distributed optimization problem.
And there's actually like the talent for this
is fairly scarce right now.
And it just basically turns into this insane thing
running on tens of thousands of GPUs.
All of them are like failing at random
at different points in time.
And so like instrumenting that and getting that to work
is actually an extremely difficult challenge.
GPUs were not like intended for like 10,000 GPU workloads
until very recently.
And so I think a lot of the infrastructure is sort of like
creaking under that pressure.
And we need to like work through that.
But right now, if you're just giving someone a ton of money
or a ton of scale or GPUs, it's not obvious to me
that they can just produce one of these models,
which is why it's not just about scale.
You actually need a ton of expertise,
both on the infrastructure side, the algorithms side,
and then the data side and being careful with that.
So I think those are the major components.
The ecosystem is moving so quickly.
Even some of the challenges we thought existed a year ago
are being solved more and more today.
Hallucinations, context windows, multimodal capabilities,
inference getting better, faster, cheaper.
What are the LLM research challenges today
that keep you up at night?
What do you think are immediate enough problems
but also solvable problems that we can continue to go after?
So I would say on the algorithm side,
one thing I'm thinking about quite a bit is
this like distinct split between diffusion models
and autoregressive models.
They're both ways of presenting
probability distributions.
And it just turns out that different modalities
are apparently a good fit for one of the two.
I think that there's probably some space to unify them
or to like connect them in some way
and also get some best of both worlds
or sort of figure out
how we can get a hybrid architecture and so on.
So it's just odd to me that we have sort of like
two separate points in the space of models
and they're both extremely good.
And it just feels wrong to me
that there's nothing in between.
So I think we'll see that sort of carved out
and I think there are interesting problems there.
And then the other thing that maybe I would point to is
there's still like a massive gap
in just the energetic efficiency of running all this stuff.
So my brain is 20 Watts roughly.
Jensen was just talking at GTC about
the massive super computers
that they're gonna be building now.
These are, the numbers are in megawatts, right?
And so maybe you don't need all that to run like a brain.
I don't know how much you need exactly,
but I think it's safe to say we're probably off
by a factor of 1,000 to like a million somewhere there
in terms of the efficiency of running these models.
And I think part of it is just because the computers
we've designed of course are just like not a good fit
for this workload.
And I think Nvidia GPUs are like a good step
in that direction.
In terms of like the, you need extremely high parallelism.
We don't actually care about sequential computation
that is sort of like data dependent in some way.
We just have these, we just need to like blast
the same algorithm across many different sort of
array elements or something you can think about it that way.
So I would say number one is just adapting
the computer architecture to the new data workflows.
Number two is like pushing on a few things
that we're currently seeing improvements on.
So number one maybe is precision.
We're seeing precision come down from what originally was
was like 64 bit for double.
We're now down to, I don't know what it is, 456
or even 1.58 depending on which papers you read.
And so I think precision is one big lever
of getting a handle on this.
And then second one of course is sparsity.
So that's also like another big delta I would say,
like your brain is not always fully activated.
And so sparsity I think is another big lever.
But then the last lever I also feel like
just the one moment architecture of like computers
and how they build where you're shuttling data in and out
and doing a ton of data movement between memory
and the cores that are doing all the compute.
This is all broken as well kind of
and it's not how your brain works
and that's why it's so efficient.
And so I think it should be a very exciting time
in computer architecture.
I'm not a computer architect,
but I think there's, it seems like we're off
by a factor of million, thousand to a million
something like that.
And there should be really exciting sort of innovations there
that bring that down.