Did it all get started? Take us back to when you really started all of this.
Well, that was the summer of 95. I had no money whatsoever.
I was working, doing research in Silicon Valley on a completely different subject
and trying to start this company at the same time.
And when it came time to decide do I want to do graduate studies or do I want to start this company
and I decided to start the company, I had no money.
As a graduate student I would have received a scholarship and a stipend and so forth.
In starting the company I had nothing. I had no income source.
So we found that an office was actually cheaper than an apartment in Silicon Valley.
So we got this dinky little office that had a leaky roof.
It was just the nastiest place you can imagine.
And you lived in it too?
And I lived in it too and showered at the YMCA.
This lasted for about three or four months.
And the reason we chose this office in addition to it being really cheap
was that there was an internet service provider on the floor below.
So we were able to get really cheap internet access by drilling a hole in the floor
and connecting to their server directly.
You know, this industry is so young and we don't really know where it's going.
But what do you see as the future of the internet?
I think the internet is the superset of all media.
It is the be all and end all of media.
One will see print, broadcast, arguably radio,
essentially all media folding into the internet.
And what the internet amounts to is it's the first two-way communication medium
that is intelligent.
It allows consumers to choose what they want to see, when they want to see it,
and whether that be radio, whether that be print, whether that be television broadcast.
I think it's going to revolutionize all traditional media.